#### EARLY ADOPTER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER · CREATOR

### East Rutherford, NJ 07073

□+1 (551) 206-0263 | 🗷 afreay@villanova.edu | 🔏 www.anthonyfreay.com | 🖫 anthonyfreay | 🛅 anthonyfreay

## Summary \_

A software engineer who uses curiosity, drive, & modern technology to solve problems & improve technical skills. Actively pursuing a full-time software engineering or full-stack developer position. Recent internship experiences at BNY Mellon has given exposure to how an application is designed, developed, & deployed within a wide-scale enterprise environment, as well as the importance of Test-Driven Development. Always ready to learn new technologies & continually grow by pursuing technical & non-technical challenges.

### Education

Villanova University (VU)

May 2020

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & PSYCHOLOGY

Villanova, PA

Awards: O'Toole Presidential Scholar

**Completed Courses:** Data Structures & Algorithms I & II, Platform-Based Computing, Computer Systems I & II, Discrete Structures, Analysis of Algorithms, Theory of Computation, Information Visualization, Database Systems,

& Software Engineering

**Current Courses:** Human-Computer Interaction

## Skills

**Programming** Advanced: Java , Golang, HTML/CSS/JS

Intermediate: ReactJS, OpenAPI Spec (Swagger)

DeploymentsIntermediate: Docker, ArtifactoryDatabasesIntermediate: MongoDB, MySQLLanguagesEnglish (native), Spanish (fluent)

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

BNY Mellon Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2018

SUMMER TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

Jersey City, NJ

- Overview: Given freedom to fully design, develop, & deploy a full-stack URL shortening service using Golang, ReactJS, MongoDB, Nginx, & Docker company-wide, reaching 35 countries and 52,000 employees
- Front-end: Minimally designed & developed using ReactJS, served with Nginx, & deployed in its own container using Docker
- **Back-end:** RESTful API developed using Golang, visually documented using Swagger.io, URLs mapped & stored using MongoDB, & deployed in its own container using Docker

**BNY Mellon** Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

SUMMER TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

New York, NY

 Overview: Develop & deploy an automated regression test of an API user interface leveraging Java & Selenium Webdriver

# **Leadership**

### **Villanova University Tech Crew (VUTC)**

Aug. 2017 - Present

SENOIR STAFF MEMBER

Villanova, PA

- Assist in the facilitation of Villanova University's event production needs & on-boarding new members
- In the 2018-19 academic year, produced 31 events including Orientation, Special Olympics, & Commencement
- Resident content creator for all social media platforms

# **Projects**

simple-url personal-site

Recreating & optimizing BNY project, will then integrate & substitute different databases & front-end technologies Designed, developed, & deployed personal-site to refine web development skills & improve digital presence

## **Hobbies**